Kevin Andres

137-1606-6712 | kevin.andres@epitech.eu WeChat: kev_Dr3 | kevinandres.com



Java Full Stack Developer

Software engineer with 3+ years of enterprise experience in full-stack development, mainly using Java and ReactJs/Angular, and participating in the complete product development lifecycle. Passionated by designing and producing well-segmented code; motivated by answer users' needs with solutions and tackle challenges with creativity.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Java Solution Architect

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Everis - Worldwide IT consulting company brand of NTT Data

Glasgow, UK

- Took part in the modernization of ASP.Net websites following PWA norms. Achieving 100 scores on Lighthouse, integrating notifications, cache, offline mode and optimizations
- In charge of designing and developing a complete PushNotification ecosystem using Java & ReactJs
 - API using Spring managing push notifications and events triggered by third party services
 - Dashboard secured with Kerberos to administrate registered websites and manage data reports
- Successfully deployed applications on JBoss and APIs behind WSO2

Developer C# .Net

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Linnworks - leading E-commerce management software in UK

Portsmouth, UK

- Responsible for the complete project life-cycle with customers: design, billing, coding and deployment support. Successfully delivered a hundred of projects while respecting dead lines and code quality.
 Promoting customer-centric approach.
- In charge of designing solutions to expand the core features to answer customers' needs
 - C# macro using multiple APIs and complex SQL scripts
 - Angular applications providing data management and UIs
 - API integration for big providers such as Global-E
- Took park in the development of a shipping integration for Magento 2.0

Java Full Stack Developer

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

Bordeaux, France

- Formaltis french startup providing management software
- Agile team with daily meetings; successfully handled short deadline sprints
- Developed a modern web management application with Java Spring and AngularJS
 - Developed backend services, repositories(Hibernate JPA) and API routes
 - Designed web interface, numerous angular components & services
- Took part in the conception of a whine trading prototype to present it to investors

EDUCATION

Master Information Technology - Epitech Paris

Sep 2012 - Jan 2018

Master Software Engineering - Beijing Jiaotong University

Sep 2016 - Jun 2017

SKILLS

- Languages: French , English
- Java: Spring Boot, Hibernate/JPA/Mybatis, Spring Security & Kerberos, Maven, RestAPI
- JavaScript & Web: HTML, CSS, ReactJs, AngularJS & Angular, Express.js, NodeJs & NPM, Bootstrap
- Database: MySQL, SQLServer, OracleSql, MongoDB, Elastic Search
- Tools: Agile processes, Git, Jira, Intelij, Nginx, JBoss, AWS, Windows/Linux